YUEHAO WANG

wangyh3@shanghaitech.edu.cn \(\rightarrow \) Homepage: http://yuehaolab.com

INTRODUCTION

I am a junior undergraduate majoring in Computer Science at ShanghaiTech University. My research insterests include Computer Graphics, Computer Vision and Deep Learning. My recent research focus on neural rendering technology and graph neural networks. I am also passionate about website design and game development.

EDUCATION

ShanghaiTech University

2017-2021

Bachelor of Science

Computer Science, School of Information Science and Technology

EXPERIENCE

Virtual Reality and Virtual Computing Center

Jul 2018 - Present

Undergraduate Student Researcher

Shanghai Tech University, Shanghai

- · Advisor: Prof. Jingyi Yu
- · I mainly work on research projects related to Computer Graphics, Computer Vision and Deep Learning. My recent work focus on neural rendering and graph neural networks. I am also a designer and maintainer of the lab's website.

Attitude Research Lab

Sep 2018 – Present

Technical Support

Shanghai Tech University, Shanghai

- · Advisor: Prof. Lifeng Yang
- · My major work include generation of testing data and analysis of experimental data, as well as developing and maintaining experiment platforms and management systems.

Institute of Mathematical Sciences

Sep 2019 – Jan 2020

Teaching Assistant of MATH1112

Shanghai Tech University, Shanghai

- · Instructor: Prof. Yunfeng Jiang
- · Linear Algebra (MATH1112) is a fundamental mathematic course for undergraduates. This course covers basic contents in linear systems, determinants, linear transformation, vector spaces, etc. My responsibility in this course includes grading students' homework and exams, giving dicussions to students every week, as well as answering students' questions.

School of Information Science and Technology

Sep 2018 – Jan 2019

Teaching Assistant of CS100

Shanghai Tech University, Shanghai

- · Instructor: Prof. Laurent Kneip
- · Introduction to Computer Programming (CS100) is an introductory course for all students majoring in Computer Science. This course mainly teaches students essential programming skills in C/C++ and Python. As a teaching assistant, my duty is to give recitations to students every week, grade quizzes and exams, also answer students' questions.

HONORS

• Citi Financial Innovation Application Competition: 1st Place Issuer: Citigroup

(Nov 2019)

• 2019 The Challenge Cup: First Prize (May 2019)

Issuer: Shanghai Municipal Education Commission

• 2018 hackShanghai Hackathon: 2nd Place (Jul 2018)

Issuer: THE Hack Team

PUBLICATIONS

1. Minye Wu, Yuehao Wang, Qiang Hu, Jingyi Yu, **Multi-view Neural Human Rendering**, accepted by *IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR)*, 2020. [Pdf] [Code]

SKILLS

Languages

Chinese (native), English (Limited working proficiency, CET-6)

Programming Languages

Python (proficient), C/C++ (highly familiar), HTML5/JavaScript (proficient), MATLAB, C#, R

Frameworks

NumPy, SciPy, scikit-learn, Pytorch, Pandas, Unity, OpenGL, WebGL, Qt, OpenCV, Docker, Nginx, NodeJs, ReactJs, Django

Operating Systems & Softwares

macOS (daily use), Linux (proficient), Google Chrome (proficient), Visual Studio Code, Jupyter Notebook, Sublime Text, Microsoft Office, LaTex

PROJECTS

Reinforcement Cache We adopt a reinforcement learning-based method to cache replacement strategy, aiming to improve the miss rate of existing traditional cache replacement policies. The main idea of modeling is to regard the strategy as a MDP so that we can employ DRL to learn how to make decision. [Pdf] [Code]

Offer Pool Application for foreign universities is a tough and important problem for students who want to study abroad. We utilize data mining techniques to predict admission of target universities. With text data crawling from related websites, we train a model which receives your major, TOEFL, GRE, GPA, target universities, etc., and output probabilities that target universities will give you offers. (Excellent course project of Web and Text Mining)

Shadow Scent A mobile game which is friendly to visually impaired people. After desk research and interviews about entertainment of visually impaired people, we design this game aiming to improve video game's user experience and sociability for those vulnerable people. [Github] (The best course project of Design Thinking Roadshow)

Pylash is a 2D game framework in Python, which was developed when I was a high school student. Inspired by my experience designing and developing video games, this framework is integrated with various modules including 2D graphics rendering (based on PySide2), event systems, tween animation, media systems, SAT collision detection, etc. [Github]